Ashley Phillips

Email: ashp1621@gmail.com

Other contact details are redacted in this version of my CV. Please email me for my full CV.

PROFILE

SUMMARY

I have worked on many different types of applications from big data & real-time analytics to marketplace platforms, with experience in several programming languages and frameworks across the full stack, which has given me a deep understanding of the software life cycle and the reality of having to balance careful design and best practices with time constraints.

EDUCATION

University of Brighton 2011 – 2014 BSc Mathematics 2:1

KEY SKILLS

<u>Front-end</u>: React, React Query, Redux, CSS (Tailwind, SCSS, styled-components) <u>Back-end</u>: Lambda, Python, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Postgres, Database Design

<u>Full-stack:</u> JavaScript/TypeScript, C++, Java, C#, WebSockets <u>DevOps</u>: Docker, AWS, Vite, Webpack & Babel, Bash, Nginx

Testing: TDD, BDD, Cypress, Selenium, Mocha, Cucumber, Jasmine, Chai

OTHER SKILLS

Documenting APIs, Algorithm and software design patterns, Statistical analysis, French (B2+)

PAST EMPLOYMENT

January 2024 - July 2024: Student of French (B2+)

Learned French, mostly by myself / online. Obtained B2 – C2 in the TCF Canada exam.

Senior Software Developer, Plentific Ltd, London UK February 2022 – January 2024

Frontend: TypeScript, React, React Query, Alt.js (Flux)

Worked on a marketplace platform for contractors and property agents. I led several projects from conception to release, and was the go to person for refactoring large modules of unruly code. I made heavy use of React Query here, which replaced Flux, simplified the data flow and reduced unnecessary data fetching.

Senior Software Developer, Feedr Ltd, London UK January 2021 – February 2022

Full-stack: JS & TS, React, MongoDB, Node.js, iOS & Android

Worked with various services, web apps and mobile apps to connect food suppliers with employers. Duties involved owning projects, unit testing, feature development/enhancement, code reviews.

Software developer, iManage, London UK June 2019 – June 2020

Frontend & infrastructure: JS, Docker, React, Redux, Ramda, Cypress, Styled Components

Worked on the frontend, and devops. Created/improved features to allow users to extract data from potentially millions of documents via AI. I also created a custom solution to run cypress tests in parallel, which massively sped up completion time of the test suite.

Frontend developer, SuperCarers, London UK March 2018 – June 2019

Frontend: JavaScript, Python, React, Redux, Styled Components, Jekyll, Selenium, Jest, Jasmine, Enzyme, Chai

Did feature development for a marketplace type of app where people looking for carers can find them, and carers can bid for work, as well as various in-house admin tools for managing carers.

Software developer, Dev2Rights, London UK July 2017 – November 2017

Full-stack: JavaScript, Node.js, React, Flux, AWS (Lambda, EC2, API Gateway, S3, RDB, CloudFront, CloudWatch, IAM, JavaScript SDK), PostgreSQL

A development agency working on a recruitment app aimed at the trades. We made heavy use of AWSLambda, S3, CloudFront, React & Flux.

Software Developer at Ancoa, London UK Feb 2015 – April 2016

Full-stack: C++, Qt framework, JavaScript, HTML & CSS, Dart & AngularDart, Linux, Git, PostgreSQL

I created algorithms to help detect fraudulent behaviour in stock markets, as well as contributing to other areas of the system, data-integration, database management, linux build system, desktop and web front-end, client APIs and some client-facing tasks and attendance of Fintech events. Joined the web team full-time for last 5 months there and helped develop the web interface.

Graduate Developer at Sword APAK, Bristol UK July 2014 – Feb 2015

Full-stack: C++ (.NET), SQL Server

Worked closely with business analysts to enhance and develop new features.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Spaced repetition app (Sep - Dec 2020)

JS, Docker, React, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Database Design

Personal project to create a <u>spaced repetition</u> app, as I was unhappy with what was already out there while learning Japanese as a hobby (<u>Memrise</u> and <u>Anki</u> being the main ones at the time).

Client-server Room package (2016/17)

JavaScript, Node, WebSockets

The Room package is designed to be used whenever there are multiple clients communicating with each other via a server, with otherwise complex functionality made much easier to implement.

Samples, git repo, tutorial & API Docs:

Server: https://github.com/Git-Ashley/server-room
Client: https://github.com/Git-Ashley/room-samples
Samples: https://github.com/Git-Ashley/room-samples

API Docs: https://github.com/Git-Ashley/room-samples/blob/master/api-docs.md

Lobby/Chat App (2016/17)

JavaScript, Node, React, Redux, Socket.io, Express.js, CSS3, HTML5

A lobby with a chat room which has been integrated with the loop-less game server project mentioned below. Players can choose to create new instances of this game, or join one. This project inspired me to write the Room package, and has itself been re-written to use the Room package.

Loopless game-server (2016/17)

JavaScript, Socket.IO, Node.js, HTML Canvas

Multiplayer game experiment with JS and Node for the backend with Socket.IO. Built using JavaScript with no other third party libraries; The back-end runs on a loop-less game-server and is completely event driven, with collisions and positions only being calculated as and when they need to, rather than 30 times per seconds (as is usually the case), which greatly reduces server load. Multiple players can log in and shoot at each other and shrink/enlarge in size. Socket.IO has since been abandoned in favour of regular WebSockets (provided by Room package).

Personal website (2016/17)

JavaScript, React, Redux, Handlebars, AWS, Linux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, passport (local, google, facebook strategies), Socket.io, bcrypt, Nginx

Website has had 3 re-writes. First version used vanilla JS with handlebars. Second version was written using React with the third version with React + Redux. https://www.ashphillips.com

Auslander-Parter Algorithm (2014/15)

Java, Algorithm design

Software which demonstrates various Graph Theory algorithms written in Java, with the option to execute algorithms on custom drawn graphs.

https://github.com/Git-Ashley/Graph-Theory-Algorithms/blob/master/src/Algorithms/ AuslanderParter.java

Unreal Engine 5 (2023 - Present)

C++, BluePrints, UE5 API

A hobby prototyping games.